Specificity in CSS.
CSS 权重（Specificity）
Specificity is about the way that
权重是关于浏览器
the browser puts different commands above each other, right?
如何处理不同命令的方式
We've seen examples of how CSS rules can be coming from all over the place.
我们已经了解了几种引入 CSS 样式的方式
You might have one rule that's inline,
你可能使用了一些内联样式
and another set of rules that are coming from an external style sheet.
同时又有一些来自外部的样式表
One thing might have an ID,
某个元素可以拥有 id
but it also might have a class.
同时也拥有一个 class 类名
So you can't have moments where there's clashing style.
所以有时候你会遇见冲突的样式
So we need our browsers to have a way to deal with this.
这个时候浏览器必须知道如何处理它们
We need a hierarchy to tell them.
我们需要一个统一的规则
So the way that it works in CSS is that,
在 CSS 中的处理规则是
type selectors or what you could think of as the ground level.
类型选择器是最低的等级
Type selectors are buttons or headers.
比如 button 元素或者 header 元素等等
So these things will have what we consider a generic styling to it.
这些东西会有一些通用的样式
They're easy to override so that anything that has that
它们可以轻易地被覆盖掉
class selector will override that.
比如 通过一个类名选择器 就可以覆盖掉
For example, if we have a button that we have said we want the background to be blue,
举个例子 如果我们有一个按钮元素 想要设置背景颜色为蓝色
and we've set that rule using that button type.
然后我们使用 button 类型选择器添加样式
But our button also has a class of favorite button.
同时 我们的按钮也有一个 favorite button 的类名
In favorite button, we've said that the background color should be red,
在 favorite button 中 我们设置了背景颜色为红色
the class will take precedence.
那么 通过类名设置的样式具有更高的优先级
So what we'll see is our button will have a background of red.
也就是说 我们会看见一个红色背景的按钮
But what if our button that had a class,
但是 如果我们的按钮除了类名
also had an ID,
还有一个 id 呢？
and that ID also had CSS attached to it?
并且也通过 id 设置了 CSS 样式呢？
Well, those rules would then overrun the class and type selectors.
是的 通过 id 设置的样式会覆盖掉类名选择器和类型选择器中的样式
So as you can imagine,
你可以想象
it can get a little bit confusing when you have had a lot of rules going on.
如果有很多的规则的话 有时候会让人感到困惑
So it's really important to keep in mind specificity when you're
所以 在你给 HTML 元素添加样式时
deciding how you want to attach CSS rules to your HTML elements.
一定要特别记住他们的权重
Now, if you find yourself in a position where you have an element that has a type,
如果你遇见了一个元素 同时拥有类型选择器
a class, and an ID,
类名选择器 和 id 选择器
and you have all these rules coming at you,
它们都有一些样式规则
and you can't figure out, what's wrong with it?
并且你不太清楚哪里出了问题
Or what's making it look different than you want?
到底是哪个地方导致了样式显示的和你预期的不一致
There is an escape patch of sorts,
还有一个最后的逃生通道
which is the important keyword.
就是使用 important 关键字
You put an exclamation point,
通过在某个 CSS 规则后面添加
followed by the word "important" after any specific CSS rule,
一个感叹号加上 important
and that will override the hierarchy that's laid out.
将会覆盖已有的所有样式
Which means, regardless of whether it's the type, class,
也就是说 不管是通过类型选择器 类名选择器
or ID selector, that line of code will take precedence because of the important keyword.
还是 id 选择器 添加了 important 关键字的总是拥有最高优先级
But, it's one of the most overused things that I see in beginning programming.
但是 我发现新手开发者经常通常会滥用这个规则
Because what the important word allows you to do,
因为 important 关键字通常
is it allows you to solve one problem immediately,
能帮助你暂时的解决问题
but then it creates a stream of problems that keep going.
但是会在随后产生一系列问题
Because what I find is that,
因为我发现
often we're using the important keyword,
当使用 important 关键字时
when we haven't done the forethought to structure and organize
通常我们没有从长远的角度来考虑
our CSS in a way that's going to make sense to us.
总体的 CSS 组织结构
So disguising that problem with
所以用 importrant 关键字
the important keyword might make you feel better in the moment,
来掩盖这个问题能够带来临时的快感
but in the long run, I think it's going to cause you more problems.
但是长期来看 它可能会带来更多的问题
So I really urge you to first try to use the type, class,
所以我鼓励你在依赖 important 关键字之前
and ID selector specificity,
先试着使用类型选择器 类名选择器
before relying on the important keyword.
以及 id 选择器
Regardless, I wish you good times in CSS land.
不管怎样 希望你和 CSS 玩得开心